mindtheproduct.com 2019-06-18

# Privacy Policy - Mind the Product

_Last update: December 19th 2018_

## Introduction

Our privacy policy will help you understand what information we collect at Mind the Product, how Mind the Product uses it, and what choices you have. Our systems and procedures are subject to ongoing change as both our technology and data practices evolve and improve, and this document will reflect that.

When we talk about “Mind the Product,” “we,” “our,” or “us” in this policy, we are referring to Mind the Product Ltd.., the company which provides the Services. When we talk about the “Services” in this policy, we are referring to our online community, events platform, media outlet, and events.

## Information we Collect and how we use it

Content and information submitted by users to the Services is referred to in this policy as “Personal Data.”. Where Mind the Product collects or processes Personal Data, it does so on behalf of the Customer in order to deliver services, or to keep the customer aware of services they have either expressed an explicit interest in or are directly related to services they are explicitly interested in.

If you create a profile on www.mindtheproduct.com, or are a ticket-holder for any of our events, you are a “customer” or “user,” as described in the User Terms of Service.

Mind the Product may access and use the Personal Information you have provided us as reasonably necessary and in accordance with your instructions to (a) provide, maintain and improve the Services; (b) as required by law or as permitted by your right to access under GDPR and (c) as set forth in our [Terms and Conditions](http://mtpcon.com/terms-and-conditions/) when you purchase a ticket to any of our events.

### 1\. Account Creation & Contact Information

Users may provide information such as an name, email address, job title, current employer, and password to create an account.

**How we use it**

We may send you Service and administrative emails and messages. We may also contact you to inform you about changes in our Services, our Service offerings, and important Service-related notices, such as security and fraud notices. If you contact us with a problem or question, we will use your information to respond. We often need to contact you for invoicing, account management and similar reasons. These emails and messages are considered part of the Services, processed as a fulfillment of our contract with you or as our own legal requirement, and you may not opt-out of them.

In addition, we sometimes send emails about new events or other news about Mind the Product, and we may also use your contact information for our own marketing or advertising purposes. These messages are processed with your explicit consent, or where we believe that both you and Mind the Product have a legitimate interest in receiving such information. You can opt out of these at any time.

We hold this data for as long as you have an active account on mindtheproduct.com.

### 2\. Comments & Media

We collect information about visitors using the Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect includes the commenter's IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).  
If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website. User-submitted images may be transmitted to image compression servers in the United States and stored there for up to 30 days.

### 3\. Embedded Media

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.  
These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### 4\. Biographical and Social Media Information

Users may provide additional information as part of their account creation process, such as a professional summary or social media links.

**How we use it**

Personal Information which is considered publicly available – such as professional biographies and social media profiles – are made visible on your mindtheproduct.com profile page, in order to facilitate networking and discovery by other users of the services with whom you might wish to collaborate or communicate. This information is provided and displayed with your explicit consent,and may be removed and hidden at any time.

We hold this data for as long as you provide it and have an active account on mindtheproduct.com

### 5\. Billing and Other Information

For Customers that purchase tickets to any of our events or who contract us to deliver training at their company, our corporate affiliates and our third-party payment processors may collect and store billing address and credit card information on our behalf.

**How we use it**

Our corporate affiliate data processors use account and contact data on our behalf to administer accounts and keep track of billing and payments, both in order to fulfil our contract with you and to fulfil our own legal requirements.

We hold this data for 7 years, as part of our legal obligation to retain financial records.

### 6\. Services Usage Information

This is information about how you are accessing and using the Services, which may include analytics through services such as Google Analytics and Hotjar (which are anonymised), and support communications with us (which contain Personal Information about you).

**How we use it**

To understand and improve our Services. We carry out research and analyze trends to better understand how users are using the Services and improve them, as part of our Legitimate Interest in improving the service we offer you. If you contact us with a problem or question, we will use your information to respond in order to fulfil our contract with you. We will also use this data to help us in investigating and preventing security breaches from happening. We work hard to keep the Services secure and to prevent abuse and fraud.

We hold this data indefinitely, in order to assess and enhance our service with regards to historical performance.

### 7\. Device & Geo-location Information

Users may provide their location as part of their profile on mindtheproduct.com. We may also collect information about the device you are using the Services on, but only to the extent that your browser supplies that information, including what type of device it is, what operating system you are using, and your approximate location based on IP address. Whether we collect some or all of this information often depends on what type of device you are using and its settings.

**How we use it**

To understand and improve our Services. We carry out research and analyze trends to better understand how users are using the Services and improve them, as part of our Legitimate Interest in improving the service we offer you. Users may provide location information that allows us to tailor our services to them, with your consent and as part of legitimate interest in providing relevant information and services to you.

Anonymised or pseudo-anonymised data is held indefinitely, in order to assess and enhance our services with regards to historical activity. Location data tied to a specific user (which constitutes Personal Data) is held for as long as you have an active account or marketing relationship with us.

### 8\. Third Party Data

Mind the Product may also receive information from affiliates and Data Processors that we use to make our own information better or more useful. This might be aggregate level information, or it might be more specific information, such as about how well an online marketing or email campaign performed (please see our [cookie policy](http://www.mindtheproduct.com/cookie-policy/) for more detailed information).

We hold this data for as long as you have an active account or marketing relationship with us.

**How we use it**

We use this additional data as part of our legitimate interest to improve the quality and relevance of the service. Certain elements of data might be granted to us via your consent and agreements with third-party Data Processors (such as Mailchimp), and are not expressly governed by this policy.

### 9\. Our Cookie Policy

Mind the Product use cookies and similar technologies to provide and support our websites and Services. We use cookies (and similar technologies, like HTML5 localStorage) to keep you logged in, remember your preferences, and provide information for future development of mindtheproduct.com - you can review our full [cookie policy](http://www.mindtheproduct.com/cookie-policy) for additional details.

## Your Choices

### 1\. Customer Data

At any time, you have the right to deactivate or delete your account on mindtheproduct.com, rendering your Personal Data either frozen (not publicly visible, and unsubscribed from all non-essential messaging) or unidentifiable (either through deletion or one-way encryption) respectively.

If you have purchased a ticket, you have the right to request a refund (with the time frames set out in our event Terms & Conditions), and to update the information we hold about you for billing and ticketing purposes, so long as that data still allows us to complete our contract with you and fulfil our legal obligations.

You have the right to update what information is associated with your profile on mindtheproduct.com, as well as to request access to the data we hold about you.

You have the right to request that erase all Personal Information we hold in association with you, so long as that information is not required for us to fulfil our legal obligations.

You have the right to withdraw any consent you have given us, at any time (for example, with regards to receiving updates or marketing communications from us).

### 2\. Other Information

If you have any questions about your information, our use of this information, or your rights when it comes to any of the foregoing, contact us at privacy@mindtheproduct.com.

### 3\. Other Choices

In addition, the browser you use may provide you with the ability to control cookies or other types of local data storage. Your mobile device may provide you with choices around how and whether location or other data is collected and shared. Mind the Product does not control these choices, or default settings, which are offered by makers of your browser or mobile device operating system.

## Sharing and Disclosure

There are times when information described in this privacy policy may be shared by Mind the Product. This section discusses only how Mind the Product may share such information.

### 1\. Customer Data

Mind the Product will never sell or share your personal data for the independent commercial gain of a third party. However, we may share Customer Data in accordance with our agreement with the Customer and the Customer’s instructions, including:

With third-party service providers and agents. We may engage third party companies or individuals to process Customer Data & Personal information in order to deliver our services; for example, for payment processing, badge-printing and networking at conferences, or sending of newsletters.

Specifically, Mind the Product hosts commercial exhibitors at our conferences, and these exhibitors will request to scan attendees’ badges to be granted access to our attendees’ contact details.

If a customer agrees to have their badge scanned by an exhibitor at one of our events, the customer understands that Mind the Product will share the customer’s basic Personally Identifying Information (name, company name, job title, email address) with said exhibitor. Where the exhibitor is using a data capture solution other than that provided by Mind the Product, the customer will be entering into a separate data usage agreement with the exhibitor, entirely independent of Mind the Product.

Regardless of the exact process of data capture, we require our exhibitors to give clear, unambiguous disclosure regarding how the scanned personal information of our customers will be used, and to only capture a customer’s details if said customer then gives their explicit consent.

### 2\. Other Information

Mind the Product may use aggregated and non-identifying information describing the demographics and behaviours of our customers and community for research or marketing purposes.

### 3\. Other Types of Disclosure

Mind the Product may share or disclose Customer Data and other information as follows:

**3.1 During changes to our business structure**

If we engage in a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, reorganization, sale of some or all of Mind the Product's assets, financing, acquisition of all or a portion of our business, a similar transaction or proceeding, or steps in contemplation of such activities (e.g. due diligence).

**3.2 To comply with laws**

To comply with legal or regulatory requirements and to respond to lawful requests, court orders and legal process.

**3.3 To enforce our rights, prevent fraud and for safety**

To protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of us or third parties, including enforcing contracts or policies, or in connection with investigating and preventing fraud.

## Security

Mind the Product takes security seriously. We take various steps to protect information you provide to us from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access or disclosure; and help ensure the appropriate use of User Personal Information. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.

No method of transmission, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## Children’s Information

Our Services are not directed to children under 13. If you learn that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information without consent, please contact us.

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may change this policy from time to time, and if we do we will post any changes on this page. If you continue to use the Services after those changes are in effect, you agree to the revised policy.

## Data Sovereignty

Mind the Product is based and operates from within the United Kingdom. Where possible, we ensure that any data processing done on our behalf takes place within the EU, but where data has to move beyond the EU, we work to ensure that our Data Processors adhere to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield, or have equivalent legal protections in place to ensure the security and privacy of your data.

If you have any questions about how your data is handled, please contact us using the details below.

## Contacting Mind the Product

Please also feel free to contact us if you have any questions about Mind the Product’s Privacy Policy or practices. You may contact us at privacy@mindtheproduct.com or at our mailing address below:

Mind the Product Ltd.  
Office 36  
88-90 Hatton Garden  
Holborn  
London  
EC1N 8PN
